Contact

Bergstigen 9 +46720159951 (Mobile) daniel_wallinder@yahoo.se

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-wallinder-b122a214 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Technical Sales Consulting Salesmanship Cold Calling

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

ZCNS Sales
ZCNP Security

Daniel Wallinder

Solna, Stockholm County, Sweden

Summary

Im very experienced in sales and have a solid background within IT related companies. I have a confidence-provoking manner. I love solution selling. Strong entrepreneurship, , Reseller, Manufacturer, distribution.

I look for solutions to problems, and how to solve business pains. I have a sell to value" mentality. Strong Negotiation skills.

Experience

Hultberg Consulting Services AB Sales Consultant July 2024 - Present (7 months) Part time sales consulting.

Commaxx Sweden
Inside Sales Specialist
September 2022 - June 2024 (1 year 10 months)
Stockholm, Stockholm County, Sweden

Baffin Bay Networks
Business Develop Manager
August 2021 - December 2021 (5 months)
Stockholm, Stockholm, Sverige

Offers cloud-based corporate security solutions to C-level companies. From prospecting to closing enterprise deals.

Sophos

Channel Account Manager Nordics & MEA January 2019 - August 2021 (2 years 8 months) Kista

Working with MSP partners all over the Nordic region as well as the Baltics and MEA. Helping new partners tranforming into MSP business from scratch. I try to support that our partners require to grow and scale their managed

services businesses and help partners moving from CapEx to OpEx models. Im also the daily contact for all MSP related issues

Nextron AS
Account Manager
August 2016 - September 2018 (2 years 2 months)
Stockholm, Sweden

Working mainly towards resellers. Selling server/storage solutions. Selling flexible IT solutions that are at the forefront of the latest technology. pipeline growth via partners. My role was to develop and maintain customer relations, as well as winning new long-term deals. Identifying and qualifying new business opportunities for existing and new customers, developing and presenting business proposals. Managing ongoing sales projects, negotiating and winning new contracts.

Zyxel Account manager December 2011 - August 2016 (4 years 9 months) Kista

December 2011 –. Working proactively with Zyxel resellers and distributors. My work is to maintain the Channel business in the relevant market area which today is Norway and Sweden. My revenue target for 2015 was around 19 million SEK. Its divided separately into three main target Sweden, Norway, Contribution. Today I manage around 400 accounts. I have every year reached my targets in a whole. For example 2014 I had a growth target of 25% which I managed to break. Here are some Key Accountabilities: Build relationships with VARs through a mix of activities and face-to-face meetings/trainings (when required) and driving sales by pushing promotions and messages prepared by the Sales Management team as well as management of a Project Pipeline. Proactively develop existing relationships with partner base and grow their ZyXEL business in line with KPI's.

Proactively look to grow the breadth of accounts trading with ZyXEL on a monthly basis in line with KPl's.

Proactively recruit new and existing customers onto training programmes.

Promote all channel activities and promotions into the partner base.

Proactively encourage accounts to join the partner programme and take advantage of the associated benefits.

Swedish Network Security Center
Sales manager
April 2010 - May 2011 (1 year 2 months)
Page 2 of 4

- Employed ideally as member of the SNSC (Swedish Network Security Center) Association in 2010. My customer contacts consisted of IT Manager, CIO and IT Technician. Among other things, my duties included demonstrating the IT security tool developed by the association.

FutureCAD AB

Technical sales

September 2009 - March 2010 (7 months)

Technical support and sales at CityData Future CAD in Sweden AB 2009. My role in the company was to answer support questions regarding AutoCAD products, both for retailers and end customers.

Insight

Client account manager September 2008 - July 2009 (11 months)

- Client account manager (CAM) at Insight Technology Solutions AB 2008. As CAM, I was responsible for selling software licenses both nationally and internationally.

Getupdated Internet Marketing

Account manager

January 2008 - December 2008 (1 year)

- Internet Marketing Consultant at Getupdated AB 2007. Handled sales of internet marketing SEO, sponsored links, banner networks and affiliate networks.

Kompass Sverige Aktiebolag

Account manager

January 2007 - December 2007 (1 year)

- Reseller / Customer Manager at Kompass Sverige AB 2006. I was responsible for the sale of business information and advertising.

Relevant Traffic

Account manager

January 2005 - December 2006 (2 years)

 Account Manager at Relevant traffic AB 2005. I was responsible for selling sponsored links and search engine optimization.

Dun & Bradstreet sweden Account manager

January 2001 - December 2004 (4 years)

- Account Manager at Dun & Bradstreet AB in 2001. My duties included sales of business information (market information and credit information).

Kanal 5

Account Manager
January 1999 - January 2001 (2 years 1 month)

Main responsible selling ads on text tv and web www.kanal5.se

Education

C₃L

Network Engineer · (1997 - 1998)

Thomasgymnasiet

Nature Science